Guide to the Office for Women in Medicine, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office for Women in Medicine, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1972-1980
RU 568
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(12 boxes)
The records consist of committee papers, reference articles, reports on organizations, conventions and scholarships, grant proposals, and statistics documenting the activities and operations of the Office for Women in Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-E (YRG 27-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of committee papers, reference articles, reports on organizations, conventions and scholarships, grant proposals, and statistics documenting the activities and operations of the Office for Women in Medicine.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Committees. II. Reference Articles. III. Reports and Papers. IV. Organizations and Conventions. V. Educational Programs, Grants, and Scholarships. VI. Community-Related Material. VII. Statistics. VIII. Other Related Papers.
Medical colleges; Medical students; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Women in medicine; Women medical students; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, 1972-1980; Accession 1983-A-027
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
  - Committees
    - Liaison Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Liaison Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Liaison Committee
      - Officers, Other Departments, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Reference Articles and Memos, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Reference Articles - Women as Medical Students, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence
        - Finseth, Katherine, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Mayerson, Evelyn, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Silver, George, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Permanent Commission, Status of Women, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Project on the Status of Women, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Status of Women Committee:
      - Connecticut Commisssion, Status of Women, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - General Correspondence, Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Minutes, Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reference Articles
    - Battered Women, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Comment on Research/Action about Women, 1978 March (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Conferences, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Connecticut Medicine, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Divorce and Women in Transition, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Equal-Rights Monitor, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Feminism, 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Household Help, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Medical School Admissions Process, 1963, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Medical School Applicants
      - Characteristics of, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Women and Minority Students, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Medicine - General Articles, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Powerlessness" by R.M. Kanter, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Pre-Med: College Graduate Pool, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Programs and Organizations for Women, 1973-? (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Role Models for Women, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Self Defense, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Sex Roles, Differences, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Socialization Information, 1967-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Women
      - Agencies for, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - General Education of, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - in the Labor Force, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Leadership Roles, Inequality, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Non-M.D., General Trends, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Older, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - as Patients, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - as Physicians; Information on Physicians in General, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Psychology of, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Women in Medicine:
      - History of, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Non-U.S.- General Articles, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - U.S.A. - General Articles, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - "Overcoming Barriers to Women in Medicine" (K.A. Finseth), undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - "Women in Medicine: Views from a Medical School" (Bodel, Short), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - "Women Physicians", 1976 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Women in the Work Force
      - Demographic Studies of Employed Women, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Health, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Men in Medicine, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Non-U.S. Women, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Psychological Factors and Effects, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Women, Characteristics of, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Women's Centers, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Yale Medicine, Fall 1978, Fall 1979 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Yale Psychiatric Quaterly, Fall 1979, Spring 1978 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Reports and Papers
    - "Descriptive Study of Salaried Medical School Faculty", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - "Report of the Yale-New Haven Medical Center Ad Hoc Research Facilities Committee", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - "A Working Paper on the Yale Teaching Enterprise", 1978 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - "Department of Psychiatry - Annual Report", 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - "Report on the Association of Yale Alumni's 1977 Alumnae Survey", 1979 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - "Report of the Managerial and Professional Committee to the Officers of the University", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Organizations and Conventions:
    - American Medical Student Association (AMSA), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - American Medical Women's Association, 1973-1981 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Association of American Medical Colleges:
      - 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Faculty Roster, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Group on Student Affairs, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - "Tables on the Current Status of Women in Academic Medicine", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Women Liaison Officers Directory, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Annual Meetings, Conferences, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 70 - 71)
    - Association for Women in Science, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - New England Women Administrators (Medical Schools) - Ad Hoc-Group, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Society for Occupational and Environmental Health - Conference, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - "Women as Healers" Exhibition, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Women in Academia Conferences (AMWA), 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Women in Medicine Conference (NYC), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Women in Science Conference, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Women's Conference (UNA), undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Educational Programs, Grants and Scholarships
    - Career Development
      - General, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Part-time Research Fellowship, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - College Seminar - "Women in Medicine"
      - Description, Related Material, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Student Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Graduate Medical Education
      - Guidelines, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - Part-Time Resources, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 85)
      - Statistics, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - National Institutes of Health
      - National Research Service Awards; Nominations, forms; NIH Study Sections, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - Reduced Time Fellowship Proposal, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Yale University
      - Financial Aid - Information Book, Grants, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - School of Medicine:
      - Interview Booklet, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Student Handbook, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - "Survival Kit for the Class of 1979", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Counseling, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Day Care:
      - General, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 95)
      - Child Care Resource Center, undated (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - Day Care Committee: Members List, Agendas, Minutes, Labels, 1972-1979 (Box 8, Folder 97)
      - Information on Opening Child Care Programs, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 98)
      - Regulations, 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 99)
      - Requests for Slots, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 100)
      - Results of Day Care Questionaire, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - "A Guide to New Haven Neighborhoods", 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Resources:
      - General, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 103)
      - Feminist Union, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 104)
      - Professional Women's Groups, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 105)
      - Support Groups, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - Support Groups, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Statistics
    - Association of American Medical Colleges Figures, 1963-1979 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Departments: Raw Data
      - Anatomy, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 110)
      - Anesthesiology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 111)
      - Cell Biology, 1973-1976 (Box 9, Folder 112)
      - Child Study Center, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 113)
      - Cytology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 114)
      - Dermatology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 115)
      - Diagnastic Radiology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 116)
      - Epidemiology and Public Health, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 117)
      - Health Science Resources, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 118)
      - History of Science and Medicine, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 119)
      - Human Genetics, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 120)
      - Internal Medicine, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 121)
      - Lab Medicine, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 122)
      - Microbiology, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 123)
      - Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 124)
      - Neurology, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 125)
      - Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 126)
      - Opthalmology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 127)
      - Pathology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      - Pediatrics, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 129)
      - Pharmacology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 130)
      - Physiology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - Psychiatry
        - General, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 132)
        - Background Information, Notes, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 133)
        - Psychiatry Searches, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - Surgery, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Therapeutic Radiology, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      - Women, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 137)
      - Women in Medicine, Office of - Miscellaneous Materials, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - Departments, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 139)
    - Faculty
      - Analyses, 1973-1980 (Box 10, Folder 140)
      - Male and Female, Track Analyses of, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 141)
    - Housestaff Questionaire
      - General Information, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      - Cover Letter, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - Extra Questionnaires:
        - Female, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 144)
        - Male, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 145)
      - Pre-Med Conference, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 146)
      - Questionnaires; Affirmative Action Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 147)
      - Reminder Letter, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 148)
      - Results, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 150)
      - Returned Questionnaires (Excluding Psychiatry), 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      - Returned Psychiatry Questionnaires, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Housestaff Survey
      - General Information, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 153)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Ladder - Clinical-Research Data (A. Wu\), 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Minorities, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - National Statistics, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Occupational Hazards of Pregnant Women Questionnaire, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 159 - 161)
    - Postdoctoral, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 162)
    - Psychiatry, Clinical - Returned Questionnaies from Faculty, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 163)
    - Research, 1967-1980 (Box 12, Folder 164)
    - Research Ranks - Raw Data:
      - 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 165)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 166)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 167)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 168)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 169)
    - Students, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 170)
    - "Women at the Yale University School of Medicine - A Statistical Report'', 1977 (Box 12, Folder 171)
    - Women in Medicine, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 172)
    - Women in Medicine at Yale, Bar Graph Statistics for, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 173)
    - Work Sheets, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 174)
    - Bibliographies
      - Women in Medicine, 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 176)
      - Yale Women Faculty Publications, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 177)
    - "A Handbook on Recruitment for Faculty and Administrative Openings", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Statements - Academic, 1977 July-1978 July (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - Women in the Health Professions, Notes for Talk on, undated (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Yale Medical School Faculty Roster, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - "Yale University School of Medicine Salary Ranges", 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 182)